

PHD PHYSICIST · AI SCIENTIST

Carrer del Roser, 27, 2nd - 08004 - Barcelona (Spain)

□ (+34) 658 87 0927 | ■ leaxsd@gmail.com | ★ leaxp.github.io | □ GitHub | □ LinkedIn

About Me

I am PhD physicist and AI researcher with interdisciplinary experience along Europe and south America. I have a PhD degree in physics from my hometown university, south of Brazil, carried with a 2 years exchange program at Heidelberg University in Germany. My first post-doc I did at Oxford University in United Kingdom. Currently I am based in Spain, working at ICFO - institute of photonics sciences developing deep learning computer vision techniques applied to super-resolution microscopy and single molecule localization.

Personal Interests: Music (and play), Cinema, Sculpture, Museums, Running, Hiking, Skating, Beach, Eating Good, Drinking Good (Specialty Coffee and Craft Beers), Rural Tourism.

Skills

Programming Python, C++, LabView, MatLab, HTML, CSS, Flask, Django

Databases MySQL, MongoDB, Amazon Web Service, Gogle Cloud Service

Machine Learning tools PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, OpenCV

Machine Learning Methods U-Net, Faster R-CNN, Autoencoders, XGBoost, ConvNets, PCA, t-SNE

Experience _____

ICFO - Institute of Photonic Sciences

Castelldefels (Barcelona), Spain

2016 - Current



POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER

- Molecular Nanophotonics Group Prof. Niek van Hulst
- Deep Learning single molecule localization
- Single molecule fluorescence
- · Scanning microscopy

Oxford University

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCH ASSOCIATE

- Kukura Lab Prof. Phillip Kukura
- Wide-field microscopy
- Ultrafast spectroscopy
- Biomolecular dynamics

Oxford, United Kingdom

2014 - 2016

Education ____



Heidelberg University

Heidelberg, Germany

2011 - 2013

PhD in Physics

- Motzkus Group Prof. Marcus Motzkus
- Vibrational microscopy
- Coherent Raman spectroscopy
- Tissues and carbon nanotubes studies

UFRGS (Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul)

Porto Alegre, Brazil

2009 - 2014



M.Sc. and PhD in Physics

- PhD Thesis Multiplex CARS applied to carbon nanotubes and brain tissues
- Laboratory instrumentation
- Physics and Optics fundamentals

Deep Learning Localization Super-Resolutiom Microscopy

ICFO (2020)

OBJECT DETECTION FOR SINGLE MOLECULE LOCALIZATION IMAGE RECONSTRUCTION

IMC cells segmentation

Ai.Vali (2019)

CELLS SEGMENTATION OF IMAGING MASS CYTOMETRY IMAGES

Endoscopy Image Classification

Ai.Vali **(2019)**

ENDOSCOPY TISSUES CLASSIFICATION WITH DEEP LEARNING

Properties Price Prediction

SharpestMinds (2017)

PREDICTION OF THE SALE PRICE OF PROPERTIES IN LONDON

Multiplex coherent anti-Stokes Raman scattering microspectroscopy of brain tissue with higher ranking data classification for biomedical imaging

Journal of Biomedical Optics (2017)

Christoph Pohling, Thomas Bocklitz, **Alex S. Duarte**, Cinzia Emmanuello, Mariana S. Ishikawa,
Benjamin Dietzeck, Tiago Buckup, Ortrud Uckermann, Gabriele Schackert, Matthias Kirsch, Michael
Schmitt, Jürgen Popp and Marcus Motzkus

DOI:10.1117/1.jbo.22.6.066005

Wide-Field Detected Fourier Transform CARS Microscopy

Scientifc Reports (2016)

ALEX SOARES DUARTE, CHRISTOPH SCHNEDERMANN, PHILIPP KUKURA

DOI:10.1038/srep37516

Sub-10 fs Time-Resolved Vibronic Optical Microscopy

J. Physical Chemistry Letters (2016)

CHRISTOPH SCHNEDERMANN, JONG MIN LIM, TORSTEN WENDE, **ALEX S. DUARTE**, LIMENG NI, QIFEI GU, ADITYA SADHANALA, AKSHAY RAO, AND PHILIPP KUKURA

DOI:10.1021/acs.jpclett.6b02387

Barrierless Photoisomerization of 11-cis Retinal Protonated Schiff Base in Solution

Journal of American Chemistry
Society **(2015)**

GIOVANNI BASSOLINO, TINA SOVDAT, **ALEX SOARES DUARTE**, JONG MIN LIM, CHRISTOPH SCHNEDERMANN, MATZ LIEBEL, BARBARA ODELL, TIMOTHY D. W. CLARIDGE, STEPHEN P. FLETCHER AND PHILIPP KUKURA

DOI:10.1002/10.1021/jacs.5b06492

Chemical imaging of lignocellulosic biomass by CARS microscopy

Journal of Biophotonics (2014)

Christoph Pohling, Christian Brackmann, **Alex Duarte**, Tiago Buckup, Annika Enejder and Marcus Motzkus

DOI:10.1002/jbio.201300052

Mapping impurity of single-walled carbon nanotubes in bulk samples with multiplex coherent anti-stokes Raman microscopy

Nano Letters (2013)

ALEX S. DUARTE, JEAN REHBINDER, RICARDO R. B. CORREIA, TIAGO BUCKUP AND MARCUS MOTZKUS

DOI:10.1021/nl304371x

